Hey there, I'm trying to create a Binary Calculator.. first off I can get the numbers into binary, but when I multiply them I get the answer in denary, if I run the same code to convert the answer in denary it goes mental...
Someone help me... what code should I be using
(I'm doing it in VB6 because this is a college bit of coursework... I have .NET 2005 at home
Conversion Binary To Binary And Conversion Of Hexadecimal To Decimal In Calculator 
Hi Folks 

i was develop one scientific calculator

1) binary to binary conversion= for example we can add one binary value (1110) + another binary value(0101) = i want this output(100 1 1)but it comes 1211 this is my question how can i rectify ? 

2) convert from hexadecimal to decimal conversions (ex)in decimal 12 to hexa is c . it wirks good ,but my question is how to convert hexadecimal to deimal (12) ?
Tks in Advance
----------------------------------------------------------------------
HARD WORK NEVER END FAILS"
Is There Any Built In Method To Convert Decimal Number To Binary Number In V.b 6.0 
Hi everybody!

can u say whether any built in method is available to convert a given decimal number to binary number?


i can develope a user defined method for this. but i think it takes some extra time to execute... since i have to call this method repetedly...

thank you,
Regards:
raghunadhs.v
How Can I Convert A Decimal Number To A Binary Number? 
How can I convert a decimal number to a binary number? Do you know if there's the function I can find in VB?

Thank you for your help!

Best Regards,

Kevin Shen
Converting A Number To Its Binary Number 
I want to convert a number to its corresponding binary number.
Eg:

105 = '1101001'

How do I do?

Thanks!
Number To Binary 
i know its highest value is 255 but how do you convert a number to binary ?

thank you.
How Do I Add Binary Number With Each Other? 
I wanna add 10010001 and 00000001 for example to get the result 10010010. How do I do that? Thanks!
Sum Of A Binary Number 
ok i have made a program in which the user enters a character form the keyboard and it returns the binary value the decimal value and the hex value 

i need to sum up the binary 1's and mod them by 2

Ex.
if the binary value is 1101101 then the sum is 5
then i mod 5 by 2 and get 1 whitch is what i need
any help would be greatly appreciated

i know how to mod using the mod command but i dont know how to sum up the binary values

this is my binary function

Public Function dec2bin(mynum As Variant) As String
Dim loopcounter As Integer
If mynum >= 2 ^ 31 Then
dec2bin = "Too big"
Exit Function
End If
Do
If (mynum And 2 ^ loopcounter) = 2 ^ loopcounter Then
dec2bin = "1" & dec2bin
Else
dec2bin = "0" & dec2bin
End If
loopcounter = loopcounter + 1
Loop Until 2 ^ loopcounter > mynum
End Function
Binary To Normal Number 
My problem is that I have a digitizer that will send to my program a binary 3D point(X value, Y value, Z value).  It will send three strands 

example: 0000 0000 0100

Now I've already typed more about binary than I know, but how do I convert that into a normal number like 3.125?  Sorry for the ignorance.  Any help is appreciated!
Convert 4byte Binary Number 
I am reading/writing stock quotes from a random access file, but the output when I print it is in scientific format. I cannot find in the help or my manual how to convert back to a single precision number. Please help.
Getting Bad File Name Or Number On Binary Open 
help! am i missing something? here's the code:

Private Sub lstFileNames_Click()

Set itmX = Me.lstFileNames.SelectedItem 'dim as listitem in declararations

Me.txtFileName.Text = itmX
Me.txtFullFileName.Text = Me.lstFileNames.SelectedItem.SubItems(1)
'subitem(1) is from fso.GetAbsolutePathName(string) and shows "C:	est.txt

strFname = Me.txtFullFileName.Text

Trim (strFname) <-- added this coz i thought maybe there was an extra space in the filename or something

'strFname = ("C:	est.txt") <--- if i hardcode the filename, open works
'iFreeFile = FreeFile() <-- this works only if i hardcode the filename, and it returns 1

Open strFname For Binary As #1 <- get here, and it errors out...error 52

Error:
MsgBox (Err.Number & ", " & Err.Description)
Close #1

End Sub
Split Binary Number Into Groups Of Three 
I have made the following coding:

Code:
Dim Part1 As Variant
Dim Part2 As Variant
Dim Part3 As Variant
Dim Part4 As Variant
Dim Part5 As Variant
Dim n As Integer
Dim x As String
Dim count As Integer
count = 0
x = txt1.Text
n = Len(txt1.Text)
start:
If n > 0 Then
Right(x, 3) = Part1
x = Right(txt1.Text, Len(txt1.Text) - 3)
n = n - 3
count = count + 1
If count = 1 Then
x = Part1
End If
If count = 2 Then
x = Part2
End If
If count = 3 Then
x = Part3
End If
If count = 4 Then
x = Part4
End If
If count = 5 Then
x = Part5
End If
GoTo start
End If
MsgBox Part1
When I use Part1 in the message box,it works. For example, if the binary is 000111011, I get 011.

When I replace Part1 by Part2, I do not get anything. I think there is a problem with the coding. Can anyone correct it??

***NOTE: txt1 is the textbox containing the binary.
Generating A Random Binary Number 
What would be the easiest way to generate a random binary number in VB?
How To Perform NOT Operation With Binary Number?? 
I have binary number, example 11010010, how do I perform NOT operation and get result 00101101? And how do I then add 00000001 to the result?
Converting A Decimal Number To Binary 
In my code I have convert numbers from Decimal to Binary and vice versa.

I have done the Binary to Decimal conversion but I am having trouble doing it the other way.

There is a HEX and an OCT function but no Binary function.

I'm sure there is something simple I am missing, can anyone help.

Thanks for your time.

SB
Convert MB Binary Format Number To IEEE 
Quick basic has a function CVSMBF to convert the old MS Binary format numbers to IEEE format numbers.


eg CVSMBF(highdata$)
The output being a single precision number eg 4.28
highdata$ being a 4byte string

I am coverting an old QB program to VB5

Sorry OnErrOr my previous query was missleading, what I really need is an answer to the above.
Program To Convert A Denary Number To Binary 
Could someone please help me on the subject. Our tutor has given us a problem. He has told us that he wants us to produce a program in vb that converts a denary number to binary. Great but I have only used vb for about 2 weeks, and managed to add two numbers together from input boxes, using a command button. If someone gets us the code I can learn from this and I would really appreciate it.
Converting Decimal Number To Binary Form 
How do I convert let's say decimal number 134 to binary form 10000110? And then how I manipulate the "bits" because after that converting the number is in second complement form and if it starts with "1" it's a negative number? So basically how do I make the converting from decimal to binary? Thanks!
Turn Binary # To Decimal Number Like How 10110 = 22 How Can I Do That ? 
Turn Binary # To Decimal Number Like How 10110 = 22 how can i do that ?
How Convert 4Bytes To 32Bits Binary Number 
How Convert 4Bytes to 32Bits Binary Number

'Get the 4 Bytes
for i = 1 to 4
    get #1, i, byteArray(i)
next

'now who can explain to me how a can change the 4Bytes to 32Bits ie.
    (10101010101010101010101010101010)
Convert Hexadecimal Number To Binary And Reverse 
How can I convert a hexadecimal number to binary and the reverse? I went to:
www.planet-source-code.com/vb 
but code is missing there :-(
Urgent plz!!!


Michael Vlastos
Company MODUS SA
Development Department
Athens, Greece
Tel: +3-01-9414900
What Is The Proper Data Type To Store Binary Eqiv. Of A Number In An Array? 
Hello all,

Trying to figure out the proper way to store the Binary representation of a number in an array. Numbers range from 0 to 65,535, and each number represented (after conversion) by 16 individual bits. Currently I am doing the following;

Code:
'Array to hold bit representation of a Number 
dim bytBits(15) as byte

Private sub ConvertToBinary(ByVal x As Long)
Dim i as Byte[indent]for i = 0 to 15
if x and 2^i then bytBits(i) = 1 else bytBits(i) = 0
Next i[/indent]end sub
So in the above, each byte holds 1 bit. This is a waste of memeory space if I were to hold 50 number conversions in memory. It is important that I have access to individual bit values elsewhere in my program. Any thoughts and ideas on how to conserve memory and still accomplish the above?

Thanks
Language Calculator (isopsephia Calculator) 
hi all 
i am new to the forum and i would like your help
i want to make a program to read words from a text file (1.295.593 bytes long) and asign them with numbers to another file. then if i put a number the program will search to find the appropriate word (or set of words to fit the number) (anyone heard about isopsephia calculator?)

here is the isοpsephia numbers at the greek alphabet
Α = 1
Β = 2
Γ = 3
Δ = 4
Ε = 5
Ζ = 7
Η = 8
Θ = 9
Ι = 10 
Κ = 20 
Λ = 30 
Μ = 40 
Ν = 50 
Ξ = 60 
Ο = 70 
Π = 80 
Ρ = 100
Σ = 200
Τ = 300
Υ = 400
Φ = 500
Χ = 600
Ψ = 700
Ω = 800

so if we have for example the word ΘΕΟΣ (GOD) should give the number 284

so if i search the number 1310 the visual basic should search for words to give me the word with same value ΑΝΘΡΩΠΟΣ (human)

best regards
any help apriciated
Bad File Number Reading Binary File 
i am writing a program for creating emergency backup for our databases. currently i encountered a 34gigabytes size single file to backup into a network location. i need to split the file and compress it for good delivery over the network. now i designed the code for splitting but have a hard time splitting the file even with 6gigabytes in size.
i use the code for opening the file as binary read only.
when i tend to split files less than 2gigabytes in size, the code seems fine but with files greater than 2 gigabytes an error 'bad file number' is raised by the vb program. i used the get# and put# statement in the program. i found out that greater than 2 gigabytes in size, the get statement could not further read data inorder to place it into a target file. can anyone help me please with this problem. i was guessing that the get # function which is in a form of get #[filenumber],recordnumber,variable is not designed for optimal sizes. 

any suggestions would be best appreciated.
Binary ASCII Hex Conversions And Reading From Binary File 
A coworker has dumped a task off on me and I am not sure were to even look for what I need. First I need to read a binary file. then I need to take this information and display the information in Hex(in a text box). For my own use I would like to disply the binary information in a text box (as 0's and 1's) and the decimal value of the binary information.

Here is copy of my program, currently messy & clunky and in need of streamlining, but I figure other people might whant the code & it should make a good starting point for some one elses program
Thanks for the Help every one!!!!



Edited by - NcNghtStkr on 8/23/2005 7:13:17 PM
Give Code In VB For Binary Conv. Like 1010 Is Binary Of 10 
Please give the code of Binary conversion in VB .
Binary And Binary Access 
hey,
First anybody got a good Tutorials talking about Binary and Binary Access...
Now whats the difference between:

Code:
Open "C:FILE.exe" For Binary Access Write As #1
and

Code:
Open "C:FILE.EXE" For Binary As #1

and how does these thing work and what does they do?
Calculator 
hi guys i would like to develop a calculator using VBA in microsoft word

-----------
| |
| |
| |
-----------
|1| |2| |3|
|4| |5| |6|
|7| |8| |9|
|x +| |- /|
|0| |=|

when user klik on |1| + |2| |=| the output will be shown in the box (the output should be 3). how can i do that? please help me. thanks
Calculator Help! 
Hi, i'm new to vba and programming in general. I am trying to write a calculator program using forms and i am confused on 2 function of the calculator: 1) When I click on the number's button(0-9) when running the program no number shows up how do I do this? 2) How do I write +,-,*,/,= functions in the program. Thank you guys for helping such a noob at coding.
Calculator 
How would i go about creating a simple form (calculator that subtracts time - just minutes and seconds) that has 3 boxes and a button.


1st box: enter time 1 (time is entered in minutes and seconds)

2nd box: enter time 2 (time is entered in minutes and seconds)


3rd box: displays the total time of '1st box' + '2nd box' when the button is pressed


Sorry, i haven't touched VB in nearly 3 years and i really need a little app like this urgently - THANKS SO MUCH IF YOU CAN HELP ME
Calculator Help. 
I am a very beginner at Visual Basic and I'm about to kill myself with this program. I can't get it to work. This week's lesson is subprograms. I just need to get my calculator to move over the next number for another number to come in. I know how to do it without subprograms, but the subprogram is required. Somebody help me. I know my subprogram should go something like this

'text is a global variable as a string

Private Sub codeforclicks (ByRef click As String)

'txt.money.text is where the output goes

txtMoney.Text = text & click
click = click +1
End Sub


My code for the button number ex. 1, 2, 3, 4 so far is this

Call codeforclicks("1")


I really don't know what I am doing so I would appricate some help. When ever i see help for calcualtors in visual basic, the help is way past my knowledge of right now so if someone could help explain it to me in simpler terms it would be appricated.


Attached files are the guidelines for the program.
Age Calculator 
Does anyone know of where i can find code for an age calculation?

i.e. if someone enters a date of birth, another text box bring up their ages in years and months?

Thanks
Calculator 
Can sum1 PLEASEEEE HELP MEE, I just need 2 create a simplle calcualtor for a class and this assignment is worth15% of my mark
here is what i hav in my FORM so far

Private Sub Command1_Click()
Dim Text1 As Integer
Dim Text2 As Integer
Dim answer As Integer
answer = CDbl(Text1.Text) + CDbl(Text2.Text)
Text3.Text = answer
End Sub

Private Sub Command2_Click()

End Sub

Private Sub Form_Load()

End Sub

Private Sub Text1_Change()

End Sub

Private Sub Text2_Change()

End Sub

Private Sub Text3_Change()

End Sub




~When i go 2 run it it says INVALID QUALIFIER with TEXT1.TEXT (5th line) highlighted
Here are my objects and commands

Text1 = First box i wanna put the first value in 
Text2 Second box
Text3. Answer box
Command1= Add button
Command 2 - Subtract


I dont know what to write in can sum1 pleasee help meeeeeeee
Calculator 
Can anyone help,

I have created a calculator program that works great.
however i have 2 buttons that i am having difficulty with.
1 is the % button and the other is the 1/x button.
my calc is a mirror image of the simple calc you get with windows.

Any help how i would code them would be great.

Thanks

Ian.
Calculator 
I been utilizing Visual Basic 5 since 3 months ago. I am trying to create a calculator program WITHOUT commmand buttons, labels, etc representing the ten digits (0 to 9). Just the user plugging in the digits manually. Anyway, I need help with it, can anyone please give me tips on how to program it correctly.
?? Calculator ?? 
hey im new here but i need to know how to do sqaure root on te calculator im stuck plzz help
Calculator Help 
hi ive designed a calculator and its working perfectly, the only one problem i have got is i donno how to do the MC, MR, MS and M+ button. i was wondering if sum 1 could help me out on how to do them. thank u
Calculator Help 
i have a calculator and i want it to round to the nearest ones digit in Text1 when i click Cmd1
can u help me?
Calculator - 
Hey

having a problem making a calculator, when i click on a button that is say,....1 and then i want to click another button say 2, it will imput 12 instead of changing the display to 2 by its own......?? how would i do this?
thanks

conrad
Calculator 
I have a line of text boxes that i want to use as a type of calculator. In the first box; txtQuantity, users put the quantity in, in the second box; txtPrice, users put the price in and the last box; txtCost i want to be able to automatically calculate the txtQuantity by the txtPrice and come up with a value when i press the button: cmdCalculate. Firstly i would like txtCost to be read only so users cannot enter a value in . How do i change the property do this in vb6?

I would then like to have several lines of the above text boxes, each one underneath the previous line. At the bottom of the form i have a txtbox: txtTotal. Is there anyway i can also use the calculate button to add all the total costs at the same time?
Calculator 
Hello. 
Im sitting at home now and building my own calculator in visual basic. 
Everything went smothly until i came to % and sin, cos and tan .
It wont work for me . Im not so good at this , can someone please give me the codes to "%,sin,cos and tan" it would be really nice.

Thanks.
Calculator (need Help, Please) 
Hi!

I´m doing a project in school where i´m going to do a calculator, but now I need help with the programming code for Sin, Cos, Tan and %! 
I really need some help, this is the last week before we should be ready with the calc... 

You can answer here or to my e-mail : dahl85@hotmail.com

//Fredrik
Calculator Help 
I am making calculator, just for the learning involved. I want it to have powers, fractions, fraction to decimal, ETC. How should I do this? I don't want the calculator to be a simple 1-step equation limited calculator either. I want it to go clear up to around 5 or so.

What would be the best way to do this? I don't want someone to do it for me, just a suggestion.

Also, I need help on how to do powers.
Vb Calculator 
I have to make a calculator which can calculate an infinate number of digits, adding and subtracting only. so if anyone could help me out on how to do this, hints tips code samples whatever would be great, thanks.
Calculator 
Hello, I am currently in the process of creating a calculator that can handle large numbers (over 60) I have got a working calculator but it can only handle around 15 numbers for some reason. This is basically what I have done so far:


Code:
Dim number1 As Integer
Dim number2 As Integer
Dim sign As String
Private Sub button_Click(Index As Integer)
If textbox.Text = "" Then
textbox.Text = button(Index).Caption
Else
textbox.Text = textbox.Text & button(Index).Caption
End If
End Sub
Private Sub action_Click(Index As Integer)
If textbox.Text = "" Then
number1 = 0
Else
number1 = textbox.Text
textbox.Text = action(Index).Caption
sign = action(Index).Caption
End If
End Sub

Private Sub clear_Click()
number1 = 0
number2 = 0
sign = ""
textbox.Text = ""
End Sub

Private Sub equals_Click()
number2 = textbox.Text
textbox.Text = number1 + number2
End Sub

Please can you advise me what to do to make this work with 60 digits?

VBstar.

Edit: Robby added [vb] tags [/ vb]
Calculator 
Hi, I'm looking for some information on how to enable a calculator to cope with binary and hex numbers. 

I have written a relatively simple calculator, (so far for decimal only). 

Any ideas? I dont have much knowledge in VB, and no this is not homework. I'm doing a nightclass in VB at my local Tech, voluntarily. 

Thanks,

Gareth
Calculator, Help Please. + - / X 
Hi there, 
I'm building a calculator,

I have a label display which shows the input. 
I want to click on a number e.g. 5 which will be displayed on the screen, followed by a + then another number e.g 9
after doing this i want to display the answer straight away.

I have already done everything except the + - / * 
could anyone please help me with the code?
Calculator! 
i made a calculator and i put the folowing code;

Private Sub num1_Click()
screen.text = screen.text & 1
end sub

Private Sub num2_Click()
screen.text = screen.text & 2
end sub

Private Sub plus_Click()
screen.text = screen.text & " + "
end sub

what the problem is, when i put the equal.. i dont know how to eqaul whatever is on the screen.text
for instance;

the text on the (screen.text) is '20 + 42'
How do i make 
Private Sub equal_Click()
(msgbox the answer to 20 + 42)
End sub

any idea?
Calculator 
Hey there I have programmed a basic calculator program but it does not have the buttons 1 - 0 and there are two text boxes where u put the numbers in. How can i use the numbers 1 - 0 and get it on a single line?

Also how can I get Cosine, Tangent and Sine calclations in degrees?
fujyuif